happy sabbath everyone how many of you
excited to be here tonight pray with me
please Heavenly Father our time is
running out we are in a race against the
clock help us to finish strong tonight
in Jesus name we pray amen have you ever
felt the pressure of time I have 38
minutes and 43 seconds to tell you what
I need to tell you let me read in the
book last day events page 212 we are
told thousands in the eleventh hour will
see and acknowledge the truth these
conversions to truth will be made with a
rapidity that will surprise the church
and God's name alone will be glorified
how many of you looking forward to that
time when thousands will be converted in
a day isn't that amazing what are they
going to be converted to they're going
to be converted to Jesus Christ amen but
the reason they're going to be converted
is because they're going to hear the
preaching of the three angels messages
amen and beloved when we think of the
three angels messages what do we think
of we think of the mark of the beast we
think of the seal of God we think of the
2300 a prophecy we think of the 70 week
prophecy we think of the twelve hundred
and sixty years we think of the fall of
Lucifer from heaven we think of many
things now I don't know if you were
excited when I said that thousands will
be converted in the day let me hear it
again Amen but do you know what that
means beloved if thousands will be
converted in a day because of the
preaching of the entire three angels
messages in a day that means beloved
that you and I better learn how to
preach the three angels messages in one
day
amen let me ask you something how many
of you have a favorite movie I know that
you're Adventists you don't go to movies
anymore but you used to have a favorite
movie yes if I were to ask you to share
with us your favorite movie in about 15
minutes or less knowing that that movie
covered a certain period of time maybe
10 years or 20 years or 50 years or 100
years how many of you think you could
share that movie in about 15 minutes or
so amen now how many of you think you
could share the great controversy the
whole thing in about 15 minutes or so
beloved here's what we're going to do
tonight we are going to cover in 36
minutes and 28 seconds the great
controversy the 2300 a prophecy the 70
we prophesy the twelve hundred and sixty
year prophecy the fall of Lucifer from
heaven the Millennium hell fire and
earth made new don't pass out it's going
to get done by the grace of God amen
beloved if I can put it this way how
many we've ever juiced anyone ever juice
before you take about 20 carats you jus
sit down into one cup right we're going
to juice the Bible tonight is that okay
time is running out there's a race
against the clock but of it please
listen carefully I Ivan subtitled this
sermon Earth's final movie The Blueprint
Earth's final movie so I'm going to need
your minds to be the screen are you
ready for the movie let's begin now by
the way please excuse me because I
usually take about an hour and 20
minutes to do this presentation I'm
going to have to speak super fast do you
forgive me are you with me are you ready
if you want the full version come see me
later i'm giving you the super juice
version tonight
the Book of Ezekiel chapter 28 begins
with an angel or allows or brings our
story begins our story rabbit with an
angel by the name of Lucifer Lucifer is
described as a covering cherub a what
everyone covering sure of not to
understand what a covering cherub is we
must go back to the old testament to the
book of Exodus where in Exodus 25 the
Bible describes our a building that God
had instructed Moses to make that
building is called the sanctuary and
inside that sanctuary was a most holy
place which was a reflection of God's
throne room in heaven are you with me in
that throne room was something called
the Ark of the Covenant and on top of it
was something called the mercy seat now
that mercy seat represents God's throne
now the mercy seat rests upon the Ark of
the Covenant listen to what that tells
us beloved that in heaven the foundation
of God's throne was his law because
that's what's found in the Ark of the
Covenant are you with me so far now the
Bible says on either side of this arc
were two angels and they were called
what covering angels that word cover
simply means to defend or protect listen
to what that tells us about Lucifer
beloved Lucifer's job description in
heaven was to protect and defend the law
of God whoa he was stood in the very
presence of God he was too he was to
guard the sanctity of that law because
it was a foundation of God's government
but the Bible tells us in Ezekiel 28
that Lucifer was perfect until what
iniquity was found in him now you help
me iniquity according to the Word of God
is sin and sin is transgression of the
law so Lucifer who was supposed to be
guarding the law of God ends up turning
against that law and thus beloved the
first war that ever broke out was over
the law
of God okay we'll work on that now now
the question is what is it the Bible
tells us that Lucifer deceived one-third
of angels amen and and and we need to
ask the question why is it how is it
that Lucifer deceived one-third of
angels did Lucifer say hey angels would
you like to be evil and join me no that
wouldn't be deception the Book of Isaiah
chapter 14 tells us that Lucifer claimed
to he said that I can be or I will be
like who the Most High let's put it
together to be like the Most High means
to be just it means to be righteous as
he is holy like he is listen to what
Lucifer was saying Lucifer was saying I
can be holy like God without some law
telling me how to do it okay have you
heard that argument before that we don't
need a law in order to be like God
beloved that's an argument of
self-righteousness and that's what
deceived one-third of angels in heaven
Lucifer didn't say hey I want to be evil
he said there are other ways to
righteousness other than obeying God
that's how the rebellion began that's
how you deceive one-third of angels so
how many of you following me in your
movie so far the Bible tells us that
Lucifer and his angels were cast out the
question now becomes why is it that
Lucifer was not immediately judged have
you ever asked yourself that question
very simple beloved the answer is a
profound one you see in the book of
Deuteronomy chapter 19 verses 16 through
19 the Bible lays out a principal
they're given to Moses in the children
of Israel whenever a controversy arose
between two parties there had to be a
third party or what everyone a third
party to discern between the two that's
only fair isn't that right now let's
take that very same principle and bring
it back to our story in heaven when
Lucifer and his angels rebel how many
sides are there in heaven to God and His
angels the
and his angels it's as though there's a
stalemate the devil is accusing God and
for God to sit over judgment of the
devil at that point in time would have
been seen to be unfair it's like you
trying to take me to court and I say
okay and I'm the judge okay so so in the
Book of Ezekiel the Bible says there are
when God is speaking of casting out
Lucifer he says Lucifer I'm gonna lay
you before kings that they may behold
you this term appears to be synonymous
with some kind of judgment and I can
imagine in my in my pastoral imagination
Lucifer scratching his head going who
are you getting good going to get to
judge me God don't you know all heaven
is polarized into two sides beloved
here's a question who would be the jury
the third party that God would use to
judge Lucifer you're looking at him
right now you see beloved listen there
is something about jury selection that
we should know when a jury is selected
they like to choose people who have
little or no first-hand knowledge of the
crime guess what where was humanity when
Lucifer rebelled we weren't even created
yet so far so good how about this a
juror must be a law-abiding
a jorum must be a law-abiding citizen
and beloved we know that Adam and Eve
were created with the law of God written
on their hearts and number three beloved
a juror must be able to discern between
right and wrong and must not be swayed
by public opinion first Corinthians 6
says know you not that we shall judge
angels we are the Kings that God created
partially to serve as jurors let me tell
you something jury duty don't skip out
so beloved Lucifer ceases creation of
man in Eagles are these the ones that
ought to judge me hmm what shall I do
what shall I do but love it if you had
access to our jury that had your fate in
their hands what would you do seek to
bribe the jury sin comes even a garden
and does he say to Eve hey Eve would you
like to be evil no no no no he says Eve
you can be like how does that sound
familiar it's the same thing he said to
the angel are you with me in your movie
so far so Adam and Eve sinned and they
are disqualified from jury selection
Jesus comes to the garden and he gives
them a promise and beloved we can
ultimately know that the gospel was
given to restore mankind to being sound
jurors who know the difference between
right and wrong and who are law-abiding
citizens are you with me so far
so now we're going to fast forward
they're our movies in a little bit and
now we're going to go down to the book
of Exodus and beloved in the book of
Exodus what we find is that God is about
to call a people out of captivity who
are they they're the Israelites now but
love it listen to me in when when
Lucifer rebelled against God in heaven
he didn't like God's Way God's what
everyone God's Way do you know what
Psalm 77 verse 13 says it says thy way O
God is where in the sanctuary so when
Lucifer rebelled against God sanctuary
in heaven he was really rebelling
against God's Way when God calls and are
the children of Israel and he is getting
ready to use them as his people who
ought to bring salvation to the world he
gives them something special I call it
the blueprints or God's g p.s the gospel
plan of salvation thy way O God is in a
sanctuary and beloved what happens is
that when you're looking for the way it
means that you must be lost so God he
looks down at Israel he says Israel I'm
gonna give you a special gift in that
gift is the way I want to use you to
take this way this GPS to the whole
world so now you can begin to understand
how much Satan have felt when he saw the
replica of what was in heaven now on
earth wait a minute this is the thing
that is to guide all people to salvation
we hated we're going to destroy it and
we're going to destroy the people who
possess it we cannot allow this truth to
go into the world you say pastor so this
blueprint what do you mean blueprint
light light like how is it the path of
salvation so we're going to take a look
now I'm going to put a picture up on the
chart up on the screen and it'll
probably only be there for a little
while I'm going to need you to memorize
this picture because I'm not going to be
able to put it up very often all right
are you with me do you see the picture
there's a picture up there no picture
there we go now you help me when you
took a bird's-eye view of the sanctuary
when you went into the outer court you
came to two articles of furniture they
were the altar of sacrifice that's right
down there at the bottom and then there
was the labor now the altar sacrifices
where animals are what sacrifice and by
the way what does that represent the
sacrifice of who Jesus Christ very good
then you have the labor that's where the
priests would wash their hands and their
feet and beloved that symbolized simply
what in the gospel baptism very good you
go up and you see the table of showbread
and the table of showbread represents
what the Word of God man shall not live
by bread alone but by every word that
proceeds out of the mouth of God then
you have the altar of incense which
represents our what prayer is very good
and then the seven-branched candlestick
represents what it represents the holy
spirit but our witness through the Holy
Spirit ye are the light of the world a
city set on a hill cannot be hid neither
do men light a candle it's your witness
and then you got into the most holy
place and there was the Ark of the
Covenant so there goes our blueprint now
do you got do you have the picture you
remember this picture so how is it that
this that this sanctuary is the is God's
gospel plan of salvation well if you
remember the picture that you just saw
if you were a trace around the outer
edges of the articles of furniture do
you know what you find you should know
because you saw it you see a cross
somebody say Amen can you imagine for
3000 years before Jesus comes upon the
scene the sanctuary prophesied that
Christ would die on a cross for our sins
he says I am the lod way the truth and
the life not only that beloved but as
you look at that sanctuary you also find
something else very interesting because
in each place where an article of
furniture is there Christ was wounded
nailing the left-hand nail in the right
hand a crown of thorns on his head he
died of a broken heart nails in his feet
but love it isn't to the point where
when he was pierced in his side okay all
right blood and water come out all right
well let's try this one God delivers his
people through this plan through this
path over and over again let's take the
children of Israel Israel are when they
were when they are were being led out of
captivity the first thing God did was he
told them to make a sacrifice and put
the blood on the post what article of
furniture what article of furniture the
altar of sacrifice very good that's
Exodus 12 in Exodus 14 they're on their
way to freedom and then Pharaoh says
what have I done I changed my mind go
get them and what does God do he opens
the Red Sea come on some money what is
that it's the it's the labor it's
baptism who after they get to the other
side that's Exodus 14 after they get to
the other side and next to the 16 guess
what happens they're like we're hungry
and guess what God does he reigns down
manna 21 minutes he reigns down man oh
so so so then after that I believe is
Exodus 16 our Exodus I'm sorry Exodus 17
or excess 19 where God down says to them
Israel you are my peculiar treasure my
light to the world my people that I'm
going to use for to bring salvation to
the earth and beloved what we're seeing
there is that God is bringing them in
essence to the seven-branched
candlestick in that same chapter Exodus
19 god says to moses moses i want you to
tell the people to spell to spend three
days preparing themselves to meet with
me hard preparation why because in
Exodus 20
in Exodus 20 beloved God comes down and
speaks what the Ten Commandments let's
just do a few more is that okay Jesus is
born in a manger among animals we might
say he was born on the altar of
sacrifice he is baptized at the age of
30 that's the labor he is then led up
into the wilderness where he is tented
the first temptation you thought I was
making this up turn the stone into bread
second temptation throw yourself down
from this cliff and offer a presumptuous
prayer to God third temptation I know
you came for your people your
seven-branched candlestick bow down and
I'll give you your people Jesus
overcomes all three citations and goes
on to preach the law combined with the
mercy of God or we could reverse it
Jesus left heaven his throne lived a
life of prayer of Prayer live the life
based on the word of God let his light
shine was baptized and then crucified
which way do you want in which but I but
ultimately listen to me oh how about
this Matthew Mark Luke and John all deal
with the sacrifice of Christ the book of
Acts is about baptism of the Holy Spirit
that's the labor the book of Romans
through Jude all talk about the
importance of bible study prayer and
witnessing and then revelation brings us
into the very throne room of God beloved
we ought to know this blueprint it's the
plan of salvation it's what the world
doesn't understand so now I know that
when I want to get saved there's a
process I must first accept who Christ
and if I genuinely accept Christ I will
be baptized and if I'm genuinely
baptized and funneling Christ I will
study the word I will pray
a-and I will watch witness and beloved
ultimately when you share this with your
friends about the path of salvation
guess where they ultimately are led to
all right I'll get excited for you Oh
what sobbing ever get the idea here God
the devil is angry at this plan of
salvation so watch this the entire Old
Testament is really about how the devil
is trying to destroy the people who
possess the blueprint and to destroy the
blueprint itself are you with me so it's
as oh god gives imagine it like this the
blueprint is a football and God gives us
footballer Israel and he says take it
down the field but Israel they begin
running down the field but they begin to
rebel against God and they get so
stubborn that God allows them to fall
into Babylonian captivity well what
happens we are introduced to the first
of three time prophecies in the book of
daniel by the way how many of you are
with me in the movie so far are you
following me amen okay so so so are the
first prophecy is the 70 week prophecy
now the question is what is this
prophecy all about very simple of it
this prophecy is simply God saying to
Israel Israel the one to whom the
sanctuary points will come in 70 weeks
if you are not ready to receive him and
if you continue in your rebellion I will
take the blueprint from you and I will
give it to somebody else guess what
happens Israel comes Jesus comes Israel
rejects the Christ you know what happens
when he dies the veil in the temple is
rent in two signifying the end of the
earthly blueprints Jesus as after his
resurrection ascends to heaven in a
heavenly sanctuary and the blueprint the
ball is taken from literal Israel and
given to spiritual Israel guess what we
just went through the entire Old
Testament
and we have 16 minutes to go the clock
is ticking God gives Israel the gift of
tongues so that they can take this
message of a heavenly sanctuary and a
heavenly high priest into all the world
and off Israel goals down the field
nothing can stop them Satan says I got
to stop these guys so what does he do he
raises up first literal Israel to attack
spiritual Israel and then he raises up
literal Rome to attack spiritual Israel
but he finds that every time a Christian
dies it's what it's working against him
because their seed only what multiplies
so then he says I've got to change my
tactic and beloved that introduces us to
the second of three time prophecies in
the Book of Daniel the prophecy of the
twelve hundred and sixty years and
beloved this prophecy simply stated that
there would rise a power called a little
horn and this little one would seek to
cast down God's blueprint are you with
me so far are you on the edge of your
seat is your movie or you follow in your
movie so the question then becomes how
is it how does the devil use this little
horn power this this this counterfeit
spiritual power to cast down God's
sanctuary it's very simple we're going
to put our chart back up on the screen
again what happened during the Dark Ages
that's a 1200 six-year period what
happened the the Church of the Dark Ages
cast down the choose that were being
taught by the sanctuary pastor what you
mean very simple the little the altar of
sacrifice which represented Christ's
sacrifice was cast down and replaced
with a teaching called penance Christ's
sacrifice is not enough to pay for your
sin you must pay penance the
effectiveness of Christ's sacrifice was
cast down and something was taught in
its place well what about the labor
which represents baptism that the church
of the dark ages said we're going to
substitute in
int sprinkling in the place of genuine
baptism that calls for confession and
repentance not only did they do that but
they went up into the holy place and
said the table of shewbread which
represents the Word of God mad you can't
understand the Word of God for yourself
only the priest can explain it to you
and they said listen we're gonna tweak
the traditions of of the church are more
important than the Word of God not only
did they do that beloved but they
reached up unto that altar of incense
which represents prayer and they said
you can't create a God you have to go
through priests in fact they even
created their own their own two
compartment room / a curtain okay with a
man sitting in the place of God hearing
the confessions of other men they put
out the light of the church thus
creating the dark ages and then they
went up into the most holy place and
took the law and took that seventh-day
Sabbath and cast it down and put in its
place of first day Sabbath shall we
despair what is God gonna do now can you
can you see it in your movie because
what I would listened there was one more
prophecy called the 2300 year prophecy
and this prophecy stated that at the end
of 2,300 years which would be in what
year 1844 at that time the sanctuary
would be one cleanse and some Bible say
restored so watch this you know what God
begins to do over a period of five
hundred years he begins to restore every
truth that had been cast down during the
Dark Ages there was a man by the name of
John Wycliffe who comes upon a scene in
the 1300s and what John Wycliffe does is
he translates the Bible into the
language of the common people thus
restoring the table of showbread amen
beloved as Avila if I was the
the 1300s I've been following John
Wyclif all around but in the 1400s a man
by the name of Martin Luther is born and
Martin Luther begins the Protestant
Reformation in the 1500s and and what
Martin Luther does is he restores the
truth that it is a sacrifice of Christ
that pays for our sins not penance are
you with me if i was living in that time
i think i would have been a Lutheran
praise god for the Lutheran movement
beloved in the 1500s a man by the name
of John Calvin also couple comes upon
the scene the founder of the
Presbyterian movement and John Calvin
has a special burden for prayer he says
we can go directly to the throne of God
for ourselves and what John Calvin does
beloved is he effectively restores the
altar of incense in the 1600s there was
a man by the name of John Smith who upon
studying his Bible said wait a minute
you can't baptize infants Franklin
you've got to be fully submersed and
confessed before or repent before you're
baptized he became the founder of the
Baptist movement the files in the 1600s
I think it would have been a Baptist in
the 1700 but I would a man by the name
of John Wesley comes upon the scene and
John Wesley is the founder of the
Methodist movement and John Wesley has a
special burden for getting the gospel
out into the world and he effectively
beloved restores the seven-branched
candlestick let your light so shine who
feel like I'm in a race 10 minutes and
23 seconds below one more article of
furniture is left to be restored hmm
okay no no no what movements what God
call upon the scene in the eighteen
hundreds you're gonna make me you are
gonna make me get excited all by myself
aren't you you're gonna do it I can't
believe you
you're gonna do it what movement what do
you call upon the scene in the 1800's to
restore the final piece of missing truth
beloved listen to me you are not a
seventh-day Adventist by accident this
movement has a prophetic birth
certificate beloved you are not an
Adventist by accident you are not some
other movements but other God has called
you for such a time as this beloved it
is this gospel that's why the first
angels message begins to go forth with
the everlasting gospel going into all
the world because it is this gospel this
gospel could have been preached during
the dark ages because it had been taken
away but by 1844 everything had been
restored but I've been listen to me all
Adventists are are Baptists Methodists
we just kept taking the truth and moving
it on listen in 1982 there was a
football game Cal State vs Stanton it
was called the play there were four
seconds left on the clock Cal State was
down by one point the band had already
begun to celebrate all Stanton had to do
was kick the ball off and then they
figured the game is over what are the
odds of the other team returning the
ball and Winnie so they kicked the ball
off and down the field of all goals &
and Cal State gets the ball and they
begin running and as the first guys
running someone tackles him but before
he hits the ground he tosses the ball to
his teammate on the other side the band
is already marching on the field people
are on their feet celebrating the second
guy gets the ball he's running and the
commentator is beginning to have his
voice raised because the second guy gets
tackled but before he hits the ground he
passes the ball on the third guy the
same thing the fourth guy the same thing
the fifth got the same thing the sixth
guy they're screaming at this time
everybody's on their feet and that six
guy runs right into the
endzone billaba listen to me the devil
his band is on the field they think the
game is over they think that you as
Adventists are a beaten people beloved
I'm just telling I'm just saying that
God wants us to finish the game that's
all I'm saying they love it listen to me
there is no time left on the clock okay
1844 was the last time prophecy in my
mind see the angels on their feet are on
their wings just like people would be on
their feet of the game and they're
cheering for us they're saying come on
take it into the end time I'm in the end
zone off God's people go down the field
the first angels message the second
angels message the third angels message
beloved it's all there and beloved
listen to me I got a son this up the
three angels messages is nothing more
than the message of Noah kid in the arc
ok now they didn't know you didn't get
it so let's write again get into the ark
get into the ark before it's too late
beloved why because the seal of God is
found in the ark and those who are
outside of the ark will be marked for
death the Angels with the seven last
plagues are seen coming out of the most
holy place why because those who receive
the plagues are those who rejected what
was found in the most holy place our
message is to get into the ark Psalm 91
says he that dwelleth in the secret
place of the Most High shall abide under
the shadow of the Almighty and you jump
down about 10 verses it tells us that no
plague okay no plague
Jesus comes he cracks the sky the dead
are raised they go to heaven for jury
duty
but I would listen to me it went the jug
when the books were opened back in 1844
it was very simply this Satan is
accusing God's people and the reason God
opens the books is not to try to condemn
you but to prove Satan a liar so that
when Satan says he did this and she did
that God says while my book says that
they repented the books contain key
evidence to save you not to destroy you
so the Angels say just enjoy my ways o
God you judge righteously now now when
the window when the judgment against the
millennial what happens we'll of it is
that the the righteous get to see the
books and they to join the chorus of
angels Justin true other ways Oh God and
now we get to the end of the millennium
when God comes down and he resurrects
the wicked dead and beloved the Bible
while we are told that listen when the
wicked debtor resurrected in that time
this world will turn into the biggest
movie theater the earth has ever seen we
are told that in panoramic view say that
with me panoramic view everyone will
watch the movie Earth's final movie
Ellen White says each actor recalls
their role but ever do I want you to be
this is reality TV this is noemi belief
I don't want the wicked looking at me
and saying you saw this movie and didn't
tell me about it you you told me about
spider-man you told me about whatever
other movie you told me about Harry
Potter you didn't tell me about the
movie that counted and whatever now
comes that time where God must destroy
the wicked and I gotta do this briefly
two minutes left for other time is
running out time is running out God must
destroy the wicked my beloved understand
the reason why God uses fire is not
because he's mad but because he's long
you see me know that God is described as
a consuming fire but Song of Solomon
tells us that fire is like a consuming
love you ever been in love before
husband's please raise your hand very
good you felt that fire that's what God
is like beloved he is fired his city's a
city of fire his throne is a throne of
fire and he wants us to be able to dwell
in that fire and not be consumed but I
didn't want to get to the presence of
God you better be fireproof and so
another God God just like when God told
Moses the burning bush and move said how
is it this bush burns and it's not
consumed God was trying to show Moses
listen this is my ideal for humanity he
wants us to be able to stand in his
presence just like Shadrach Meshach and
Abednego were thrown in that fire and
were not consumed beloved listen to me
it's the righteous that's that burn
forever
the wicked are not fireproof they burn
up God will not allow it into heaven
because heaven would be held for them do
you see how the devil flips it God would
those great big arms stretches out and
embraces the wicked one last time and in
that embrace the wicked feel the love
that they have rejected and they say
just and true are thy ways Oh God there
is a unanimous decision to destroy the
weekend beloved God rebuilds planet
Earth and the Bible says from Sabbath to
Sabbath we will worship God you want to
know why because just as Israel just as
Israel was commanded to keep the Sabbath
as commemoration of their delivery from
captivity so we will ever keep the
Sabbath as a reminder of our deliverance
from this earth
it's the movie we have 44 seconds left
the love you please understand that God
has called you for such a time as this
stop sitting on the fence stop sitting
on the fence if you've doubted your
Adventism doubt it no more if you said I
can't give a Bible study I can't
understand listen please know that God
has a plan for you listen I can you
imagine giving this study to somebody
and just having them hear these words of
truth beloved listen to me God how many
believe God can use you you believe God
can use you pray with me Heavenly Father
we ask that you would please teach us
Lord what it means to love you and to
serve you and to go into this world with
your GPS showing the lost the way to
salvation in Jesus precious name we pray
amen and amen